谢谢你们让我把哈雷放你们房间
Thanks for letting me put Halley in your room.
没事  不客气
Yeah, no problem.
对了  佩妮  她貌似吐了点在你的小熊上
Oh, and, Penny, she kinda threw up on your stuffed bear.
没关系
Oh, that's okay.
《星球大战》里一种长相类似泰迪熊+西施犬的外星生物
那小熊是我的伊沃克娃娃
Hey. Tha-That's an Ewok and it's mine.
对啊  所以才没关系啊
Yeah, which is why it's okay.
你看  他床上就可以摆伊沃克
See, he gets Ewoks in his bed.
《星球大战》里的角色  长得像人形长毛狗
你也摆了楚巴卡娃娃  够了
You've got Chewbacca; that's enough.
该电影中的一名超级英雄角色  外形是一只浣熊
我之前是摆了《银河护卫队》的浣熊娃娃
I used to have the stuffed raccoon from Guardians of the Galaxy,
但它都要被小桂子舔秃了
but Cinnamon licked it raw.
唯一适合你说淫秽狗故事的地方跟时间
There's a time and place for your randy dog stories,
就叫做...
and...
不存在的
it's never and nowhere.
不许再说跟性有关的事了
Yeah, no more stories about sex,
所以艾米  该你来聊聊了
so, Amy, that brings us to you.
最近上班我们有在做
Well, at work we've been doing
一些有趣的神经假体研究
some interesting research with neuroprosthetics.
厉害
Neat.
2003年开播的美国青春肥皂剧
我最近在重看《橘子郡男孩》
I've been rewatching The O.C.,
所以大家的生活都过得很有建设性
so we're all leading productive lives.
我们在研究个计算机接口
We've been working on a computer interface
用来通过大脑波动来控制机械义肢
that can use brain wave patterns to control robotic limbs,
但我们在试图定位
but we're having a little trouble localizing
脑电帽的信号时  碰到了困难
the signal from the EEG cap.
你想过加入传感器相位阵列
Oh, well, have you thought about adding a phased array of sensors
来得到更好的定位效果吗
for better localization?
其实我还真没想到过
Actually, that never occurred to me.
我也真没想到过
It never occurred to me
我会有想念聊伊沃克的时候
I would miss the Ewok conversation.
太好了  因为我刚上网又买了一个新的
Good, 'cause I just bought another one on Amazon.
我这个项目其实可以请一位工程师来帮手呢
You know, I could use an engineer on this project.
那真是太好啦
Well, now, this works out great.
霍华德就是工程师
Howard's an engineer.
他肯定认识能胜任这份工作的人
I'm sure he knows someone qualified.
她说的人就是我  谢尔顿
She was talking about me, Sheldon.
我完全能胜任
I'm perfectly qualified.
对啊  华仔是世上最强工程师
Yeah, Howie's the world's best engineer.
他的咖啡杯上就有这句话
It says so right on his coffee mug.
你还送一个这种杯子给他啊
Aw, you got him a mug?
我送的
I did.
不过这也不是什么示爱大比拼啦
But it's not a competition.
对啊  我多年前早输得一败涂地
Yeah, I lost that battle years ago.
霍华德  那你有兴趣吗
So, Howard, are you interested?
这还用说吗
Are you kidding?
如果我可以用大脑控制机械手臂
If I could control robot arms with my brain,
我就能做好多好多事呢
I'd be able to do so many things.
真的吗  你早就会用大脑控制人类手臂
Really? Because you've been controlling human arms
可至今没见你有什么建树啊
with your brain for years and not much has come of it.
第十一季  第五集
你在读什么呢
Hey, what you reading?
育儿书
A parenting book.
天啊  我们...
Oh, my God. Are-are we...?
什...  屁啦
Wha... No!
如果怀了  你觉得我会用这种方法说吗
You think this is how I would tell you?
你...  你居然坐在那里看书
Well... You're sitting there with a book.
感觉什么都有可能了啊
It felt like anything was possible.
伯纳黛特忘在这里了
Bernadette left it here.
是吗  有什么有趣的东西吗
Yeah? Anything interesting?
我刚看到一个婴儿头从妈妈下面出来的图
Well, I just saw a picture of a baby's head crowning,
希望你曾享受过性福  因为再也不会有了
so I hope you enjoyed sex, because we're done with that.
你们好啊
Hello.
谢尔顿  你好吗
Hi. Hey, Sheldon, what's up?
你还记得换艾米载我上班后
Well, remember how disappointed you were
你当时有多失望吗
when Amy started driving me to work?
你说有就有吧...
Sure, uh...
有时人们会在失望的时候露出超大的笑容
Sometimes people smile a big smile of disappointment.
我有个好消息告诉你
Yeah, well, good news,
艾米因为要带霍华德熟悉环境  提早上班了
Amy had to go in early to show Howard around her lab,
所以你有幸载我上班
so you get to drive me.
他失望的微笑
Aw, his smile of disappointment
变成了愉悦的皱眉
has turned into a frown of joy.
还好啦  我都载他多少年了
It's fine, I've been driving him for years.
多载一天又如何
What's one more day?
而且我还有新的乘车游戏能玩
Oh, and I've got a new car game we can play.
叫"猜猜这是什么警笛声"
It's called "What siren am I?"
杀了我吧
Kill me.
艾米  你的实验室太厉害了
Amy, your lab is amazing.
C型臂X光机
A C-arm fluoroscope,
颅脑超声波
a cranial ultrasound...
瞧瞧那台咖啡机
And look at that coffee maker.
对啊
I know.
我在实验室费用报告里
On our expense report,
把它称为"爱德华多"
I listed it as "Eduardo,"
我的哥伦比亚人实验助理
My Colombian lab assistant.
-就是这个了吧  -是的
- So this is it? - Yes.
我们要用它来测量大脑波动
We are using it to map brain wave patterns
然后把波动转换为电脉冲
and then converting them into electrical impulses
就能用来操控任何东西啦
that can be used to control anything
无论是轮椅还是机械人都行
from wheelchairs to robots.
从你手上的戒指来看
Based on that ring on your finger,
我觉得你对操控机械人十分有一套
I'd say you're pretty good at controlling robots.
说话小心点  你吐槽的可是我未婚夫
Careful, that's my fiance you're talking about,
小心我操控他揍你
and I can program him to hurt you.
猜不出来  法国警车吗
I don't know. Uh... French police?
很接近了
Oh. So close.
是比利时救护车
Belgian ambulance.
准备好答下一题了吗
All right, you ready for your next one?
先提醒你  这声音有点烦人
Just a warning, this one's a little annoying.
先...  先休息一下吧
Let's take a little... little break,
我有点头疼
I'm getting a headache.
玩得正高兴你怎么就头疼了呢
Aw, right in the middle of our fun game.
对啊  奇了怪了
Yeah, weird.
所以...
So...
霍华德与艾米共事
Howard and Amy working together--
挺有意思  是吧
that's interesting, huh?
应该还行吧  我想
Eh. It's all right, I suppose.
毕竟以前艾米抱怨同事的时候
Uh, when-- usually when Amy complains about her coworkers,
我都当耳边风
I just tune her out,
现在我能加入话题然后疯狂开喷
but now I'll be able to join in and pound away.
你不会嫉妒霍华德吧
You're not jealous of Howard, are you?
当然不会
Of course not.
我唯一会嫉妒的
The only engineer I'm jealous of
是能给火车鸣笛的那种火车司机[工程师]
is the one who blows the train whistle.
这让我想到了一个新游戏
Ooh, that just gave me an idea for a new game,
-叫"这是什么鸣笛声" -火车
- "What whistle am I?" - Train.
我告诉你  我本来要出的题是茶壶
For your information, it was going to be tea kettle,
不过那是个在火车上的茶壶
but the tea kettle was on a train,
这题就算你对吧
so I'll give it to you.
想给你的脑电图传感器加上相位检测
If we add phase detection to your EEG sensors,
我就得重写大部分的编码
I'll have to rewrite most of the code.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
我这双手就是用来做三件事的
?Well, these hands were made to do three things:
近景魔术  编码
close-up magic, writing code,
许多国家与文化都有皮影戏这种传统文化
还有演出下流皮影戏
and the dirty shadow puppet show
这最后害我被踢出犹太学校
that got me kicked out of Hebrew school.
你们好啊
Hello.
真是意外之喜啊
Hi. What a nice surprise.
我就过来看看你们俩相处得如何
Well, I just came by to see how you two were getting along.
一切都很顺利
Well, everything's going really great.
听你这么说就放心了
Oh, that's nice to hear.
我也希望你们两个能合作愉快
I was hoping you two would enjoy working together.
你眼睛一眨一眨是干嘛
What's with the blinking?
是摩斯密码
It's Morse code.
方便我们聊...
So we can talk about...
又不会伤害到...  的感情
...without hurting... 's feelings.
谢尔顿  我不懂摩斯密码
Sheldon, I don't know Morse code.
我懂  如果你对我有什么意见
I do. And if you have something to say,
你可以当面对我说
you can say it to my face.
好吧
Oh. All right.
太久没用有点生疏  你能再说一次吗
I'm a little rusty. Could you say that again?
她说差不多八点回来  那到底是几点
She's going to be home at "Eight-ish." Like, when is that?
八点零一分  零二分
8:01? 8:02?
哪门子的科学家用"差不多"这种词
And what kind of scientist uses "-ish"?
我来用用看
I'll give it a go.
载你回家的路上  我"差不多"置身地狱
My ride home with you was hellish.
谢尔顿  如果你想和我们一起吃晚餐
Sheldon, honey, if you want to join us for dinner,
我们非常欢迎
you're more than welcome.
不了  谢谢
No, thank you.
我觉得我今晚没什么心情
I don't think I'd be very good company tonight.
那您一边儿去吧
Well, then out you go.
到底怎么了
Okay, what is going on?
自从艾米开始和霍华德一起工作
Well, ever since Amy started working with Howard,
她就没回过家
she hasn't been home.
那不是今早才开始的吗
Didn't that just start this morning?
那她回过家了吗
And has she been home?
换做是我  我也会挺不爽的
You know, that would frustrate me.
你觉得不爽吗
Does it frustrate you?
确实
I-It does.
我能理解
I get that.
当事情不如意的时候
You know, it's okay to feel frustrated
感到不爽也是很正常的
when things aren't going your way.
我想是吧
I suppose.
也许这没什么大不了的
Ah, maybe it's not that big a deal.
不不  你有权感到不爽
No, no, no, your feelings are valid.
不如你先去洗手洗脸
Now, why don't you go wash up,
等晚饭准备好了我们再叫你
and we'll call you when dinner's ready.
好吧
Okay.
你做了什么  你是女巫吗
What did you do-- Are you a witch?
不  我一直在看伯纳黛特的育儿书
No, I've been reading Bernadette's parenting book.
这简直就像谢尔顿考题的答案本
It's like the answer key to the Sheldon test.
-太不可思议了  -就是说啊
- That's amazing. - I know.
但这书只适用于新生儿到五岁的小朋友
But, you know, it's only birth to five.
等他六岁时我们该如何是好
What do we do when he turns six?
带他去动物园  然后把他丢在那儿
Take him to the zoo and leave him there.
伯纳黛特
Hey, Bernadette.
你好啊  拉杰
Oh, hey, Raj.
-霍华德不在家  -我知道
- Howard's not here. - Oh, I know,
这周每晚他都在实验室  和他的职场老婆一起
he's been in the lab every night this week with his work wife.
奇怪了
That's weird,
我还以为他的职场老婆正站在我家厨房呢
I thought his work wife was standing in my kitchen.
别那么尖酸刻薄嘛
Don't be snippy.
我是来看看你过得怎么样
I came to see how you were doing.
有什么需要帮忙的吗
Like, uh, do you need help with anything?
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
是有些家务活儿
There are a few things around the house
我等着让霍华德去做
that I've been waiting for Howard to get to.
那个烟雾报警器...
The smoke alarms...
不  我是指情感上
No, I meant emotionally.
你现在有什么感觉
How are you feeling?
我感觉你不是真的来帮我的
Like you're not really here to help me.
依然那么刻薄
Well, still snippy.
一切都挺好的
Everything's fine.
霍华德对他的工作感到很兴奋
Howard's really excited about his work,
他最近心情都超好  我很为他骄傲
he's been in a great mood... I'm really proud of him.
我也还穿得下我高中时期的裤子呢
And I can fit into the pants I wore in high school.
拜托  我们没必要对彼此说谎
Come on, we don't need to lie to each other.
你说得对
You're right.
我有个正在长牙齿的宝宝  我怀孕了
I have a teething baby, I'm pregnant,
我明天有份提案要交
I have a proposal due tomorrow.
我没空听你逼逼
I don't have time to hear about
你有多想念我的老公
how much you're missing my husband.
我现在知道他为什么一直加班不回家了
Well, I think I know why he's been working so late.
欢迎回家
Welcome home.
工作怎么样啊
How was work?
很好  霍华德有个想法...
Great. Howard had an idea for...
别老提工作了
That's enough about work.
你才刚到家
Aw, you just got here.
你快坐下  让我宠宠你
You need to sit down and let me pamper you.
听起来很不错
Oh. Well, that sounds nice.
我有个小东西要给你  帮你放松
I got you a little something to help you relax.
谢尔顿  这真是最贴心  最...
Sheldon, that is the sweetest, most...
这  这是什么
What... what is this?
我们量子认知项目的笔记
The notes from our quantum cognition project.
我想着今晚我们可以好好学习[摩擦]一番
I thought we could spend the evening grinding away on it.
我才刚到家  我很累
I just got home, I'm tired.
霍华德让你心累  我懂的
Of Howard, I know.
你我二人
So how about you and me
今晚来造点有爱的科学  怎么样
make some beautiful science together?
谢尔顿  我也想和你做这个
Sheldon, I want to work on this with you,
但今晚不行
just not tonight.
要不我们明天早点起床做  怎么样
What if we get up early and do it in the morning?
我保证  到时我会更投入
I promise, I'll be way more into it.
你知道吗
You know what?
想当年  某人愿意整晚不睡
There was a time that you would've been happy
陪我通宵做一整晚
to stay up and collaborate all night with me.
然后早上醒来又继续做
And then wake up in the morning and do it some more.
好吧  但能不能速战速决
Fine, but can we make it quick?
不行
No.
速战等于让我一个人做全部  那你去睡觉得了
If you're just gonna make me do all the work, then go to bed.
但如果你出房间时
But don't be surprised if you walk out here
撞见我正在自己解决  可别吓着
and catch me doing it myself.
谢尔顿发短信叫我载他去伯纳黛特家
Sheldon's texting me to drive him to Bernadette's.
你打算怎么回他
Well, what are you gonna say?
正好新出了竖中指的表情包
Well, they did just introduce the middle finger emoji.
此时不用  更待何时
If it's not for this, I don't know what it's for.
不不  他只会以为
No, no, no. He'll just think that means
你是说"一分钟后到"
"Be there in a minute."
也许书里会有解决方法
Maybe there's something in the book that will help.
值得一试
Worth a shot.
好  我们来看看
Okay. Let's see, let's see.
"咬其他小朋友"
"Biting other children"?
他有时会这样  不过这个改天再解决
Well, sometimes, but... problem for another day.
好  等等  这个
Okay, wait, wait. Here we go.
"让他有选择的权利
"Let him have ownership of his choices.
让他从你可以接受的选项中做出选择"
Allow him to choose from options that are acceptable to you."
好吧  我姑且一试
All right, I'll give it a try.
"我可以两小时后载你去  或者你可以叫优步"
"I can drive you in two hours or you can take an Uber"
很好  现在他觉得自己有得选
Good. See, now he feels like he has a choice.
他决定叫优步
He's gonna take an Uber.
居然成功了
Wow, it worked.
除非他咬司机  不然就太成功了
Unless he bites the driver, yeah.
现在他们居然连周六都要上班
And now they're working on a Saturday?
你能相信这种荒唐事吗
Can you believe them?
你预期中的周末是这样的吗
Like, is this how you envisioned your weekend?
并不是
No, it is not.
整件事都很令人恼火
This whole thing is maddening.
我真的很忙
I'm really busy.
我没时间听你抱怨
I don't have time to listen to you complain.
你也在抱怨啊
Hey. You're complaining, too.
"谢尔顿  你来干什么"
"Sheldon, why are you here?"
"谢尔顿  苹果泥是给宝宝吃的"
"Sheldon, the applesauce is for the baby."
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我只是希望能让霍华德跟我现在一样生气
I just wish I could make Howard feel as angry as I'm feeling.
或许你可以做些他喜欢的事
Well, maybe you could do something he likes
让他妒忌你
and make him jealous.
比如什么
Like what?
美国小说家马克·吐温1876年发表的长篇小说  主人公调皮捣蛋  追求自由
你有没看过《汤姆·索亚历险记》
Have you ever read Tom Sawyer?
没有
No.
家务  他喜欢做家务
Chores. He likes chores.
哪种家务
Ooh. What kind of chores?
我想想
Well,
你可以给烟雾探测器换电池
you could change the batteries in the smoke detectors.
那会让他嫉妒到发疯
That would drive him crazy.
好棒哦
That's great.
他一定会气得头顶都冒烟
Oh, he'll be so mad smoke will be coming out of his ears.
然后烟雾探测器就会探测到有烟
And then the smoke detectors will detect it.
慢着  等一下
Wait, wait, now, hold on.
你刚才为什么问我汤姆·索亚的事
Why'd you ask me about Tom Sawyer?
我只是对你很感兴趣
I'm just interested in you.
你这小嘴比你的苹果泥还甜呢
Well, you are sweeter than your applesauce.
我现在把等待期延长
Okay, I'm gonna extend the wait time and have it poll
再把模数转换器从最低位调到最高位
the A-to-D converter at the top of the loop instead of the bottom.
很厉害嘛
Oh. That's impressive.
这算什么  你去把大脑模型打开
You think that's impressive, take apart that brain model.
我的妈呀  梅花三  我选的就是这张牌
Oh my God-- three of clubs. That was my card!
你怎么变的...
How did you...?
以前我都是让牌出现在我的裤裆里
I used to make it appear in my pants,
可人力资源部不许我这么搞了
but HR said I had to stop doing that.
还需要等多久才能做测试
So, how much longer till we can test it?
编译还需要一段时间  估计得等几分钟吧
Well, it needs to compile, so it's gonna be a few minutes.
看来我们给自己争取到了一个休息时间
Sounds like we've earned ourselves a break.
你想不想听点尼尔·萨达卡
You want to hear some Neil Sedaka?
知道吗  这才是你最厉害的魔术
You know, that's your greatest magic trick,
这读心术真是太牛了
'cause you just read my mind.
美国知名歌手尼尔·萨达卡歌曲《Calendar Girl》
♪ 我好爱  好爱  好爱我的挂历女孩 ♪
♪ I love, I love, I love my calendar girl ♪
♪ 美丽的月历女孩 ♪
♪ Yeah, sweet calendar girl ♪
♪ 我好爱  好爱  好爱我的月历女孩 ♪
♪ I love, I love, I love my calendar girl ♪
♪ 每一年的每一天 ♪
♪ Each and every day of the year ♪
♪ 一月 ♪
♪ January ♪
-♪ 你开始了... ♪  -哎哟哟
- ♪ You start the year all fine... ♪ - Well, well, well.
说自己忙得像蜜蜂  然而你俩却在跳舞
You say you're busy as bees, yet here you are, dancing.
虽然蜜蜂也会跳舞
Although I suppose bees do dance,
但人家是为了告诉其他蜜蜂花粉位置
but their dance lets other bees know where the pollen is,
而你们的舞可不是
and yours does not.
所以我的逻辑  尽管有些许的迂回
So my logic, despite that slight detour,
还是正确的
does track.
我们只是在等代码编译
We're just waiting for my code to compile.
你来干什么呀
What are you doing here?
我顺道来问你想不想和我去看电影
I stopped by to see if you wanted to go to the movies with me.
我很愿意
Well, I-I'd love to,
但我们马上就要进行测试了
but we're just about to test the interface.
可能要等一段时间
It could take a while.
好吧  兄弟  虽然不关我的事
Okay, buddy, it-- it's not my place,
但博纳黛特有点感觉被冷落了
but Bernadette's been feeling a little abandoned
因为你花太多时间待在实验室里了
with all the hours that you've been putting in.
那你还拉他去看电影
You just asked him to go to the movies.
是呀  但我跟他的关系就算是他婚后
Yeah, but our weird relationship was grandfathered
也同样享有特权  但你们的没有
into their marriage, and yours was not.
好的  我给烟雾探测器换了新电池
Okay, I put new batteries in the smoke detectors.
衣服洗了没
Did you do the laundry?
洗完了
I sure did.
他肯定气得头冒蒸气
He's gonna be steamed.
就像我熨他衬衫时用的熨斗一样
Just like his dress shirts.
至少他还有烤箱可以清理
At least he can still clean the oven,
所以应该没事
so that's something.
他想得美  你家的钢丝刷在哪里呀
Oh, that's what he thinks. Where's your steel wool?
给你
Right here.
我俩真是一对好搭档
We make quite the team.
那当然
Sure do.
两位  你们相信吗
Guys, you won't believe this.
我去学校看望霍华德和艾米
I stopped by the university to check in on Howard and Amy,
他俩玩得可开心呢
and they were having fun.
别担心  他回家以后就笑不出来了
Well, don't worry. He won't be having any fun when he gets home.
我把他最爱做的家务都做完了
I did all his favorite chores.
你在瞎说什么呢
What are you talking about?
霍华德最不喜欢做家务了
Howard hates doing chores.
等等  那为什么伯纳黛特告诉我...
Wait, then why would Bernadette tell me that...
伯纳黛特
Bernadette.
你是利用我出了名的好骗来帮你做清洁吗
Did you play on my well established gullibility to clean your house?
当然啦
Sure did.
我本该摔门而去
Well, I would storm out of here,
但手套和钢丝刷已经在我手里了
but I already have the gloves and the steel wool,
我本来也很喜欢清理烤箱  快让开
and I really do love cleaning an oven. Move.
她拐我做了所有的家务
She made me do all her chores,
这还不是她的原创
and it wasn't even her idea--
是偷《汤姆·索亚历险记》里的招数
she stole it from Tom Sawyer.
得了吧  别发神经了
You know what? This is crazy.
人家霍华德和艾米是一起工作  别乱想了
Howard and Amy are working together-- get over it.
莱纳德  你干什么呢
Leonard, what are you doing?
"必要时得喊停"
"Knowing when to say when."
这不是什么大事
This is not a big deal.
这是一件大事
It is a big deal.
霍华德让艾米习惯了欢笑和音乐
Howard's getting Amy used to laughing and listening to music.
万一她回家也想玩这么疯呢
What if she expects that madness at home?
你说得有道理
Yeah, that is a good point.
你能把自己的感受说出来  我为你骄傲
I'm really proud of the way you're able to express your feelings.
谢谢  我只是太生气了
Thank you. I'm just so angry.
你知道  每个人都会生气的
You know, everyone gets angry.
所有的爸比们和妈咪们也会生气
Even mommies and daddies.
你不会觉得现在应该"肯定他的行为"吧
You can't think this is the right time to "Validate his behavior."
那我们试试"父母统一战线"如何
Okay, what about "Presenting a united front"?
不如试试你溺爱他  让他永远无法成长吧
What about you coddling him and he's never gonna learn?
听着
Look.
你听起来很生气  我觉得你能够
You sound frustrated, and I'm really proud of the way
把自己的想法说出来  非常棒
you're able to state your opinion.
谢谢
Thank you.
等一下  不对
Wait, no, no.
你别用书上的东西对付我
Don't use that book on me.
等一下  什么书
W-Wait, what book?
佩妮一直在用博纳黛特的育儿书对付你
Penny's been using one of Bernadette's parenting books on you.
什么  他还不是一样
What? So has he.
你们凭什么把我当小孩对待
Wh-What makes you think you can treat me like a child?
你用的是芝麻街大鸟形状的洗发水
Your shampoo comes in a Big Bird bottle.
那是因为成人洗发水会辣到我的爷们眼睛
That's because the adult shampoo burns my man eyes.
你在忙什么呢
Hey, what are you working on?
我的天  你还在呢
Oh, my God, you're still here?
我当然还在啦
Well, of course I'm here.
我能理解你的感受
I know what you're going through.
真的吗  你家也有一个缺爱的印度人吗
Really? You have a needy Indian man in your house?
本来是有的  后来他到你家来了
I did, but then he came over here.
这就是咱们有孩子之后的模样吗
So is this how it's gonna be if we have kids?
你就这样把一切怪在我的头上
You're just gonna throw me under the bus?
如果你用溺爱谢尔顿的方式教他们  那就会
If you spoil them the way you do Sheldon, then, yeah.
我的办法很有用好嘛
Uh, my way was working.
我觉得你生气
Okay? I think you're just upset
是因为在某些方面你跟我没得比
because there are some things I am better than you at.
你不能把介词放在句子的结尾
Well, you can't end a sentence with a preposition,
所以你比我厉害的肯定不是语法
so clearly, not grammar.
你这么聪明  你猜你这句话聪不聪明
If you're so smart, was that a smart thing to say?
看情况  在我回答之前
That depends. Before I said it,
咱俩今晚的滚床单还有戏吗
was sex tonight still on the table?
-没戏了  -那我说的话没毛病
- No. - Then it's fine.
一旦我们能让它运作起来
You know, once we get this operational,
我们就有可能实现无线化操作了
we could probably figure out how to make it wireless.
那就太棒了
That'd be amazing.
谢尔顿发信息来了
Oh, that's Sheldon.
他在生莱纳德和佩妮的气
Oh, he's upset with Leonard and Penny.
还有博纳黛特
And Bernadette.
还有马克·吐温
And Mark Twain.
博纳黛特之前也发来了信息
Yeah, Bernadette texted earlier.
拉杰快把她逼疯了
Raj is really getting on her nerves.
最近咱俩的确加班有些多
Well, I guess we have been working late a lot.
我们要不现在收工回家吧
Should we call it a night and go home?
我们也可以煮壶咖啡  继续攀登科学的高峰
Or we could brew a pot of coffee and power through.
是吗  现在都这么晚了
I don't know, it's getting kind of late.
我的表哪里去了
Hey, where's my watch?
去问问你的骷髅吧
Why don't you ask your skeleton?
我的妈呀  你是怎么办到的
Oh, my God. How is that even possible?!
我们俩一起玩  这真是极好的
This is great, the two of us hanging out.
之前怎么没想到呢
Why didn't we think of this earlier?
同意
Agreed.
我不需要和艾米一起看电影
I don't need Amy to watch a movie.
我也能轻松地不牵你手
I can not hold your hand just as easily.
在原著中  这个男的就是杀手
In the book this is based on, that man's the killer.